<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jammy's Cave</title><link>https://jammy.co/</link><description>Recent content on Jammy's Cave</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 James Wheatley</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 16:09:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jammy.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OAuth Explained Part 2: Authorization Code Grant</title><link>https://jammy.co/posts/2022/02/oauth-explained-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jammy.co/posts/2022/02/oauth-explained-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, I explained the OAuth protocol flow at a high-level. In this part, we will dive in to the most popular authorization grant type: the authorization code grant.
Grant Flow The authorization code grant is a redirection-based flow:
The client redirects the resource owner&amp;rsquo;s user agent (hereafter, we&amp;rsquo;ll just say &amp;ldquo;browser&amp;rdquo;) to the authorization server. The authorization server authenticates the user. The authorization server asks the resource owner for consent to give the client access to the protected resources.</description></item><item><title>OAuth Explained Part 1: Introduction</title><link>https://jammy.co/posts/2022/02/oauth-explained-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 08:22:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jammy.co/posts/2022/02/oauth-explained-1/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine I am working on a calendar app. I know that a lot of my users keep their events in Google Calendar, so I need to make sure that I can retrieve their events from Google, and send back the newly created ones. How does Google know that my app is allowed to access a user&amp;rsquo;s calendar?
As a user, when I go to https://calendar.google.com I&amp;rsquo;m asked to provide the username and password for my Google Account.</description></item><item><title>FreeBSD on XPS 13: Part 2</title><link>https://jammy.co/posts/2018/05/freebsd-on-xps-13-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 22:01:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jammy.co/posts/2018/05/freebsd-on-xps-13-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, I installed FreeBSD on my Dell XPS 13, configured wireless networking, and created a new boot environment. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;ll install some of the software that I need and start on the configuration of the system.
Display Resolution When I bought this laptop, I opted for a variant with a QHD+ screen. In hindsight, I wish I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done that. While the HiDPI situation in Linux has improved over the past few years, the experience is still far from seamless, and the situation in Windows isn&amp;rsquo;t much better.</description></item><item><title>FreeBSD on XPS 13: Part 1</title><link>https://jammy.co/posts/2018/05/freebsd-on-xps-13-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 23:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://jammy.co/posts/2018/05/freebsd-on-xps-13-part-1/</guid><description>I like to think of myself as being fairly Operating System agnostic. At home, my main desktop runs macOS and my laptop runs OpenSUSE. At work, I develop software for a Debian-based network operating system and administer CentOS VMs on VMware hypervisors.
There are two gaps here though. I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly use Windows any more (other than still rocking a Windows Phone for work), and I&amp;rsquo;ve never really seriously used a BSD.</description></item></channel></rss>